Finding Aid for the Zenna L. Serrurier Papers LSC.1057
UCLA Library Special Collections
Zenna L. Serrurier papers
1920-1966
UCLA Library Special Collections
Serrurier, Zenna L., 1906-
LSC.1057
2.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Zenna L. Serrurier (b.1906) was a counselor at Edison Junior High School (later renamed Ramona High School), and later, served as principal of Ramona High School (1948-62). The collection consists of manuscripts, clippings, photographs, correspondence, high school yearbooks, and memorabilia related to Serrurier's career as an educator and principal at Ramona High School.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Zenna Serrurier, 1964.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9929768273606533
Biography
Serrurier was born in 1906; her family came to the U.S. when she was a child; she taught in Los Angeles, California, and was a counselor at Edison Junior High School (later renamed Ramona High School); principal of Ramona High School, 1948-62.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, clippings, photographs, correspondence, high school yearbooks, and memorabilia related to Serrurier's career as an educator and principal at Ramona High School.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Memorabilia (Box 1).
Ramona High School (Boxes 2-4).
Related Oral History
The following oral history is available through the UCLA Library Center for Oral History Research:
Ramona High School: an experiment in education [oral history transcript] / Zenna L. Serrurier, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1962.
Educators -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; High school principals -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Ramona High School (Los Angeles, Calif.); Serrurier, Zenna L., 1906- --Archives.
- Memorabilia., 1952-1966 and n.d.
  - Vigil Jr. High, Pasadena High, UCLA, etc. (Box 1)
  - Ramona High., 1959-1966. (Box 1)
  - Ross High., 1960-1964. (Box 1)
  - "Through prisons, deportations, and exile in the USSR" translated by Z. Serrurier. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous reports, pamphlets, advertising mail, etc. (Box 1)
  - Proceedings from Institute on unwed parenthood., 1952 and 1954. (Box 1)
  - Material re Serrurier oral history interview (300/72). (Box 1)
    General note
    See Related Material.
  - Tape recording of Russian trip., 2 sides, 3 3/4 in. per sec. (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Supplement to oral history - not transcribed.
- Ramona High School., 1953-1966
  - Homeroom logs [for] Ramona High School., ca. 1955-1958. (Box 2)
  - Reports on girls., ca. 1957-1962.; [4 folders] (Box 3)
  - Ramona News., 1955-1966. (Box 4)
  - Cruiser., 1953-1959. (Box 4)
- Clippings, notes, book reviews, etc. concerning available literature about the Soviet Union. (Box 3)